嗨大家，歡迎來到介紹性 Python 教學，特別關注於影像處理
hi everyone welcome to introductory python tutorials with a special focus on image processing
在這段影片中，我們來快速了解一下升採樣和卷積的區別
in this video let's have a quick look at the difference between up sampling
和卷積
and convolutional
轉置操作
transpose operation
而且這兩者都可以是 2D
and that can be in 2d both of these can be in 2d
和 3D
and 3d
而且這些通常會在單位中使用
and these get commonly used in units
以及其他架構，如自編碼器
and also in other architectures like autoencoders
以及生成對抗網路
and generative adversarial networks
如果你不知道我們在說什麼單位，我強烈推薦
if you don't know what we are talking about when it comes to unit i definitely recommend
觀看最後兩三部影片
watching the last two three videos
我們討論了自動編碼器
where we talked about auto encoders
以及單位與自動編碼器非常相似，只是跳過連接部分不同
and how units are very similar to auto encoders except for the skip connection part
現在在解碼器部分
now on the decoder part
這意味著在機器學習中你會有一個較小的向量
which by definition means you have a smaller vector in terms of machine learning
在編碼器部分，你是從一個大型圖像轉換到一個較小的向量
in the encoder part you're going from a large image to a smaller vector
以及解碼器部分，您從一個小的
and the decoder part you're going from a small
張量，我應該說是從較小的張量回到大型圖像
tensor i should say smaller tensor back to a large image
同時，您是如何升級您的
while you're doing that how do you upscale your
或者提升您的影像解析度
or up sample your image right
所以
so
從較小的
going from a smaller
尺寸到較大的尺寸，這就是我們所說的，這裡有兩個選擇，主要的
size to a larger size this is what we're talking about there are two options primary
我應該說其中一個是升頻
options i should say one is up sampling
你可以根據名稱升頻你的影像
you can up sample your image as the name suggests
這意味著你正在取樣
it's sampling meaning you're
獲取像素值
taking the pixel values
你正在以某種方式擴展它們
and you're extending them in a way
你也可以進行轉置操作
and you can also perform transpose operations
首先讓我們看看這兩者之間的差異
and let's see what the difference is between these two first of all
再次提醒你，我們討論的單位是編碼器路徑，對吧
just to remind you again the unit that we're talking about you have an encoder path right
所以
so
為什麼尺寸會隨著向下移動而變小，那是因為當你應用
why is the dimension size going down as you go down that's because when you apply
最大池化操作，大小為兩乘兩，對吧，那正是
the max pooling operation with the size of two by two right that's exactly
我們用這個紅色箭頭做了什麼
what we are doing with this red arrow
這會將你的圖像大小減少一半
that decreases the size of your image by half
所以你從 256 變成 128，再變成 64，再變成 32，最後變成 16。
so you're going from 256 to 128 to 64 to 32 to 16.
在解碼器端，我們需要做完全相反的操作，從 16 轉換到 32
on the decoder side we need to do exactly the opposite go from 16 to 32
如此類推，這是我們實際上可以應用我們的 2D 上採樣的地方
and so on this is where we can actually apply our up sampling 2d
或者轉換 2D 轉置
or convert 2d transpose
現在讓我們更仔細地看一下，既然我們知道了背景
so now let's have a closer look now that we know what the context
現在讓我們更仔細地看一下這些
is let's have a closer look of each of these
所以
so
有兩種類型
there are two types
像我們之前提到的那樣
like a like we already mentioned
可以使用
that can be used
上採樣 2d 非常類似於
up sampling 2d is very similar to
最大池化，除了它顯然與最大池化相反
max pooling except it's obviously opposite to max pooling
在 2D 上採樣中，我們會重複行
where in up sampling 2d we are repeating the rows
和輸入的列
and columns of the input
我會
i'll
我會以視覺化和程式化的方式解釋這一點
i'll explain that in a visual way and also in a programmatic way in a minute
轉換 2D 轉置，顧名思義是一種卷積操作
convert 2d transpose as the name suggests is a convolution operation
好的，所以這裡有一個乘法運算，上採樣只是重複數據
okay so there is a multiplication going on upsample is just repeating the data
所以如果你有
so if you have
如果你有，我們稍後會討論到，不過讓我先不
if you have we'll get to that in a second let me not
你知道，嘗試提供你一些抽象的細節
you know try to give you abstract details
但我們會有一個視覺解釋
but we'll i have a visual explanation of this
並且不能進行 2D 轉置
and can't 2d transpose
如果你
if you
如果你想弄清楚使用哪一個
if you want to figure out which one to use
我個人沒有看到太多差異
i haven't seen much of a difference personally
使用這兩者中的任何一個
using either of these
但數量轉置已被報告會導致棋盤格伪影
but quantity transpose has been reported to result in checkerboard artifacts
好的
yeah
但比較不多
but not much of a comparison
這兩者之間的文獻可能不多，也許我漏掉了什麼
between these two is out there when it comes to the literature maybe i'm missing something
如果你們知道
if you guys know
任何這兩者之間的比較論文，請在評論中留下
any comparison paper between these two please do leave that as part of the comments
但對我而言，兩者都同樣好，我想更喜歡
but to me both are equally well i want to prefer
2D 轉置
con 2d transpose
因為這樣你也會學到一些，你知道，機密的轉置實際上會學到
because that way you're also learning some you know the confidential transpose actually learns
和上採樣那裡沒有東西可以學習
and up sampling there is nothing to learn there
希望在接下來的五到十分鐘內，事情能變得更清楚一些
okay again hopefully in the next five to ten minutes things makes a bit more sense
那麼讓我先談談上採樣
so let me start by talking about up sampling first
好的
okay
假設這是我的輸入圖像，它只是一個三乘三像素的圖像
so let's say this is my input image it's just a three by three pixel
好的
okay
現在我想進行二比二的上採樣
now i would like to perform two by two up sampling
所以這就是
so this is
基本上
basically
重複你的像素
repeating your pixels
兩倍兩倍，所以在這種情況下，我的一張圖片就是我一個像素，抱歉
two by two times so in this case my one image is just my one pixel sorry
這個紅色
of this red
正方形是四個紅色正方形
square is four red squares
然後是四個粉紅色的
and then the four pink ones
然後是黃色的，以此類推
and then the yellow ones and so on
這樣你就可以在這裡看到圖像
so you can see the image right here
是一二三四五六對六乘六
is one two three four five six right six by six
我們從三乘三開始
and we start with three by three
所以尺寸翻倍了
so the size doubled
因為我們使用的是二比二的上採樣
because we are using two by two up sampling
這正是為什麼我們在 unit decoder 中，我們從 16 變成 32 再到 64
this is exactly why we're in our unit decoder we're going from 16 to 32 to 64
因此大小會加倍
and so on because the size doubles
如果你進行兩兩操作
if you apply two by two operation
因此上採樣容易理解，你只是複製，這裡沒有任何需要訓練的東西
so up sampling is easy to understand you're just copying there is nothing to train here
你拿一個矩陣，你拿像數字這樣的東西，當涉及到卷積時，你會重複它們
you take a matrix you take like numbers you repeat them when it comes to convolution
再次進行 2D 轉置，讓我們使用相同的輸入
2d transpose again let's work with the same input
這樣可以讓我們更容易理解
so it makes it a bit easy for us to understand
這會轉換成看起來像這樣的東西，你知道的
this gets converted into something that that looks like this on you know
讓我解釋一下
let me explain this
這是一個卷積操作
so this is a convolution operation
所以我們需要定義
so we need to define
內核大小將會是什麼
what the kernel size is going to be
在這個例子中，我的內核大小是 1x1，就是 1x1
in this example my kernel size is one by one that's it just one by one
但是我的步幅是 2x2，這意味著我每次移動兩個單位
but then my stride is two by two that means i'm going two
每次一步，所以那裡有間距
steps at a time that's why there is a spacing right there
在這兩者之間是可以的，因為我的步幅是二乘二
okay in between these two because my stride is two by two
所以把這個想像成非常類似於二乘二的上採樣
so think of this as very similar to two by two up sampling
那裡正在創建這個黑暗的空間
there it's creating this dark space
但它沒有填充任何東西
but it's not filling it with anything
這裡它用這些像素值進行上採樣
here it's filling it with these these pixel values in up sampling
這裡它沒有填充
here it's not filling with
就是那裡的資訊
this information right there
現在
now
因為這是卷積操作，所以還有一些稱為權重的東西你可以定義
because this is convolution operation there is also something called weights that you can define
什麼是權重，權重基本上是卷積內的值
what are weights weights are basically the values within the convolutional
在這個例子中，大小為一對一的濾波器
filter of size one by one in this example
所以我要設置一個權重為 1，這意味著我的輸出
so i'm going to put a weight of 1 that means my output
將會具有與我的輸入相同的值
is going to have the same values as my input wherever
這裡有這個值
there is this value
我希望這樣解釋能讓你明白，我們會寫一行
i hope this makes sense again we'll we'll write a single line
或者幾行來更好地理解這一點
or a few lines to understand this a bit better
但我只想確保在視覺上
but i just want to make sure visually
我們在同一頁面上
we are on the same page
上採樣非常簡單對吧
up sampling very simple right
兩兩進行上採樣，就是複製這個卷積
two by two up sampling it's just copying this convolution
如果你需要了解什麼是卷積，請觀看關於卷積的視頻
operation you need to know what convolution is please watch the video on convolution
這裡的卷積是你有你的圖像
here convolution is you have your image
和你有一個核
and you have a kernel
你在影像的每個像素上進行卷積運算
and you're multiplying the kernel at every pixel in your image
並且你正在移動那個卷積核
and you're moving that kernel
在這個情況下，我的卷積核大小只有一個
by how much in this case my kernel size is just one
或一個接一個
or one by one
而且我每次移動兩步，這就是為什麼你有
and i'm moving it two steps at a time that's why you have
從這裡開始，它會走一、二步
from here it's going one two
一 二
one two
然後在這個方向上，一二，這裡就是你擁有這個空間的地方
and then also in this direction one two that's where you have this space
好的，現在這個空間被填滿了所有的零值
okay right now the space is filled with all values of zero
但是隨著學習，這個空間可以被填充新的值，這基本上就是
but then as you learn the space can be filled with new values that's that's basically
什麼是 2d 轉置
what con 2d transpose is
好的
okay
現在讓我們使用簡單的 Python 代碼來更好地理解這些差異
so now let's use simple python code to understand the differences a bit better
那麼讓我們跳到我們的 Collab
so let's jump on to our collab
這段代碼我將與你分享
and this code i'm going to share
所以請注意
so please pay attention to
我們現在正在討論的內容
what we are talking right now
首先，我們來演示 2D 上採樣
so first of all let's demonstrate up sampling 2d
然後我們可以進行 2D 轉置
and then we can we can do con 2d transpose
為此，我將導入
so for that i'm going to import
TensorFlow 序列
tensorflow sequential
所以我們會建立一個小型模型
so we'll create a small model
只有上採樣層
only with up sampling layer
好的
okay
所以這就是為什麼我們要進行上採樣
so that's why let's go ahead and import up sampling
當然還有輸入
and of course input
這樣我們就可以定義輸入
so we can define the input
好的，我們的數據是什麼
okay what's our data
通常我們處理的是影像
normally we work with images
但在這種情況下，我們想要確切了解
but in this case we want to understand exactly
什麼是取樣，讓我們定義一個三乘三像素的圖像
what up sampling is so let's define our own image of three by three pixels
我填充了我們的圖像
and i filled our image
或 numpy 陣列，值為一、二、三、四、五、六、七、八、九
or numpy array with values of one two three four five six seven eight nine
這樣我們可以弄清楚是否有重複的內容
so we can figure out if things are repeating
好的
okay
所以這是我的 x
so this is my x
這是我目前的圖像
which is my image for now
什麼是影像？它只是 numpy 陣列對吧
what is image it's just numpy array right
現在我要重塑它
so now i'm going to reshape it
這樣它就可以以正確的形狀進入我的神經網絡
so it's in the right shape to get into my neural network
所以我們來執行這一行
so let's run this line
然後沿著這條線
and then right along this line
所以我的形狀基本上是處理我的三乘三輸入
so my shape is basically takes my three by three input
我有一張三乘三大小的圖片
and i have one image of three by three size
它是單通道的
and it is single channel
對，我沒有很多通道
right i don't have many channels
就在那裡，那就是輸入的內容
right there that's what the input is
這已經準備好進入我的神經網絡，一旦我定義好
this is ready to go into my neural network once i define
那麼我的神經網絡是什麼
it so what's my neural network
或我的模型
or my model
那麼我將使用順序方法
well i'm going to use sequential method
而我的輸入尺寸為這個
and my input is of size this
這是三乘三乘一的大小，這是我的輸入
which is three by three by one right off size this is my input
好的
okay
然後我將添加一個大小為二乘二的上採樣層
and then i'm going to add an up-sampling layer with a size of two by two
我們已經從圖像中看到，如果我們有
so we already saw from the image that if we have
二乘二的上採樣
a size of two by two up-sampling
或圖像尺寸加倍
or image dimensions double
那麼我會期望的
so what i'm going to expect
因此從這裡的結果是一六六一，它會加倍對吧
as a result from here is one six six one it's going to double right the
每一個
for each of these
所以讓我們繼續定義這個
so let's go ahead and define this
我們馬上就會看到結果
and we'll see the result in a second
所以這是我的模型摘要
so here it is the summary of my model
你可以看到摘要已經顯示它將給我一個輸出
you can see that the summary already that it's going to give me an output of
一張影像，這裡的“無”意味著我們有一張六乘六的單通道影像
one image right none here means we have one image six by six single channel images
和有多少個參數來訓練零，沒有任何東西
and how many parameters are there to train zero there is nothing again
讓我重複一次，這裡沒有需要訓練的東西
let me repeat this up sampling there is nothing to train
好的
okay
因此，值為零，訓練參數的數量
so the value is zero number of trainable parameters
因此，如果你擔心增加可訓練參數的數量
so if you are worried about increasing the number of trainable parameters
然後如果你的網路變慢，你可以繼續使用上採樣
and then make your making your network slow you can go ahead and use up sampling
但始終記住，上採樣作為unit的一部分是會被應用的
but then always remember this up sampling as part of a unit is applied
在卷積操作之後
after a convolution operation
所以這並不是說你會大幅增加它
so it's not like you are increasing it dramatically
使用卷積 2d 轉置，你擁有卷積
with convolution 2d transpose you have the convolution
和轉置類似的內建功能
and transpose kind of built in
所以
so
所以你仍然需要訓練幾乎相同數量的
so you still have to train almost similar number of
參數
of of parameters
好的
okay
到目前為止我們什麼都沒做，我們只是將我們的影像定義為三乘三的矩陣，並重新塑造它
so far we have done nothing we just defined our image as three by three matrix reshaped it
我們定義了我們的模型為接收一些輸入
and we defined our model as taking some input
然後是上採樣層，讓我們將這個模型應用到我們的圖像上
and then just up sampling layer let's apply this model onto our image
你怎麼做到這點？其實就是使用 model.predict 對吧
how do you do that well it's just that model.predict right
所以我們使用這個模型對原始影像進行預測
so we are predicting with this model onto our original image
所以 x 是我們的輸入
so x is our input
所以當你這樣做時，我們繼續
so when you do that let's go ahead
並列印出來
and print out
原始輸入是 一 二 三 四 五 六 七 八 九 我們知道
the original input is one two three four five six seven eight nine we know that
和上採樣的
and the upsampled
這是來自的輸出
which is the output from from
或者來自我們的 model.predict 是一一二二三三一一二二三三和
or from our model.predict is one one two two three three one one two two three three and
四四五五六六，這與我展示給你的紅色粉紅色黃色盒子非常相似
four four five five six six this is very similar to the red pink yellow boxes i showed you
每一個，如果其中一個是紅色盒子，它會重複四次
each one of those if one is the red box it's repeated four times
這是上採樣，就這樣，所以這就是我的做法
this is up sampling that's it so this is how i go
從較小的圖像到較大的尺寸
from an image that's smaller to a larger size
正如你所見，這實際上不是一個很好的方法
as you can see this is not a great way of actually
使你的原始影像解析度恢復正確
getting your original image resolution back right
我的意思是
i mean
你在這裡失去了影像解析度
you are losing image resolution here
這正是為什麼在 unit 中連接非常重要
this is exactly why in unit concatenation is very important
從早期的卷積網絡
from the earlier convolutional
encoder 層卷積層到 decoder 層
encoder layers convolutional layers to the decoder layers
好的
okay
現在讓我們看看 2d 轉置實際上是如何工作的
now let's see how con 2d transpose actually works
好的
okay
那麼我們來做一個類似的
so let's work on a similar
幾乎完全相同的例子，只是這次我不是進行上採樣，而是將 con 進口到 d 轉置
pretty much the same example except instead of up sampling i'm importing con to d transpose here
好的，所以其他的完全相同
okay so everything else is exactly the same
然後在我的模型中，我將使用 con 2d transpose 來代替上採樣
and then in my model instead of up sampling i'm going to use con 2d transpose
讓我們使用我之前給你的相同示例
and let's use the same example i gave you earlier
即一乘一的卷積核大小和二乘二的步幅
which is one by one kernel size and a stride of two by two
現在這一點很重要，當我設置內核初始化器時
now this is important when i put kernel initializer
等於一次，這意味著它初始化
equal to once that means it initializes
我內核中的所有值為一
all values in my kernel with a value of one
這等同於重量等於 1
this is equivalent to the weight equals to 1
這意味著如果我有這樣的輸入圖像，它會將每個值乘以 1
which means if i have a input image of this it's going to multiply each value by 1
所以我們的值不會改變，我們將再次看到這個效果，我之前談到過
so our values don't change we'll we'll see the effect of this again i talked about
視頻中的核心初始化器
kernel initializers in a video again
如果你還沒看過那個，我強烈推薦你去看看
if you haven't watched that i definitely recommend doing that
如果你不定義這個，那麼 Keras 將使用默認值
if you don't define this then keras is going to use a default
初始化權重的方式
way of initializing weights
我相信這是一種常態分佈隨機分佈
which is i believe some normal distribution random distribution
那麼，隨機初始化會有一些變異
well random initialization with some sort of a variance
好的
okay
那麼我們來定義這個模型
so let's go ahead and define this model
和一件事，好，這很重要
and one thing okay this is important to see
現在我的步幅是二乘二
now my stride is a two by two
而我的卷積核大小是 一乘一，對吧
and my kernel size is one by one right
所以
so
這是總結，我的輸出將會是
this is the summary here my output is going to be
六乘六乘一的尺寸，完全相同的大小
the size of six by six by one exactly the same size
就像我們如果放大它的話
as we if we upscaled it
完全相同的大小
exactly the same size
因為
because
再次，步幅是，對不起，我們的步幅是兩步兩步，那正是
again stride is sorry our stride is two by two that's exactly
為什麼我們有六六一
why we have six six one
但這裡的關鍵點是查看被訓練的參數數量
but the key point here is see the number of parameters that are trained
作為我們神經網絡訓練的一部分可訓練
trainable as part of our neural network training
這是兩個參數，為什麼要一一查看內核大小
it's two parameters why look at the kernel size one by one
這意味著只有一個值
what does that mean there is one value
這意味著它正在嘗試學習，這是權重
that it's trying to learn this is the weight
另一個是偏差，記住人工神經元總是有一個權重
and the other one is the bias remember artificial neuron there is always a weight
和一個偏差對吧
and a bias right
如果有一個神經元，那麼你有兩個可訓練的參數，一個權重
so if there is one neuron then you have two trainable parameters one weight
而且這正是為什麼你有那裡的兩個參數，如果我改變我的核心
and one bias that's exactly why you have two parameters right there if i change my kernel
我認為這是一個非常有教育意義的練習，對不起，兩兩來做這個
to i think it's a very educational exercise to do this sorry two by two
然後再次運行這個
and then run this again
我的參數數量將是五個，仍然是六個六
my number of parameters are going to be five it's still six six
因為我的步伐是兩兩一組
because my strides are two by two
好的，但可訓練的參數數量是五，為什麼
okay but number of trainable parameters is five why
因為如果是兩兩一組
because if it is two by two
我有多少個
how many do i have
多少個權重，四個，對，兩兩一組
how many weights four right two by two
所以我有四個權重，網絡需要訓練
so i have four weights that the network needs to train
在訓練過程中加上一個偏差
during the training process plus one bias
為了它
for it
好的
yeah
所以你有四加一等於五，這就是為什麼你有五
so so you have four plus one five that's why you have five
所以我猜也許你知道
so i guess probably you know
當你使用三乘三的核時會發生什麼
what to expect when you have three by three kernel
好的，正確
okay exactly
如果你有三乘三，那就是九對吧，九加一，十個參數
if you have three by three that's nine right nine plus one ten parameters
那麼我們回到逐一處理
so let's go back to one by one
逐一處理是我們想要的
one by one is what we want
那麼我們繼續進行應用，好的，這就是我們所在的位置
and let's go ahead and apply this okay so this is where we are
現在
and now
讓我們應用這個模型 dot predict
let's apply that model dot predict
我稱這個模型為 one right，model one dot predict 在我們的輸入數據上
i call this model one right model one dot predict on our input data
現在我們來印出所有轉置過的數據
and let's go ahead and print out all the transposed
以及那些上採樣值
and up sample values right there
所以
so
我的原始輸入
my original input
和轉置的
and the transposed
卷積未
conv not
由於步幅為一，因此不會有任何零值
by one stride available there won't be any zeros
和你有值讓我們
and you have values let's
一個一個做
do one by one
所以當你一個一個做時，這意味著你的輸出形狀也是三個
so when you do one by one that means your output shape is also three
同原始輸入相同
same as original input
所以那裡沒有任何變化，我們也做另一件事
so there's nothing changing right there let's also do one other thing
我們來移除內核初始化部分
let's remove the kernel initializer part
和查看
and see
輸出結果應該是這樣的，這部分應該完全一樣，我們不會改變任何東西
how the output looks like this part should look exactly the same we're not changing anything
但當我們將它應用到圖像上時，我們會在這裡看到一些奇怪的數字
but when we apply that onto our image we'll see some weird numbers right here
為什麼我們會看到這些奇怪的數字
why are we seeing these weird numbers
因為這是隨機初始化的
because this is randomly initialized
權重不再是 1
the weights are no more one
所以顯然權重變成了 0.96
so apparently the weights turned out to be 0.96
在該位置
at that location
所以 1 乘以 0.96 等於 0.96
so 1 times 0.96 is 0.96
這裡的重量大約是 0.8
the weight here is somewhere around 0.8
這裡得到的結果是某個東西乘以 2
something multiplied by 2 is what you get right here
好的
okay
所以你的權重在 0 的範圍內隨機生成
so your weights are randomly generated between values of 0
和 1
and 1
然後乘以你這裡擁有的數字
and then multiplying by whatever you have here
然後你會得到這個，這就是為什麼 con 2d 我希望
and then you get this this is why con 2d i hope
我希望這解釋了 con 2d，這裡我通過一次初始化內核
i hope this explains the con 2d here i'm initializing the kernel by once
所以
so
你的輸出將會和輸入一模一樣，只是多了一些空格
your output is going to look identical to input with extra spaces
因為我們只是把這些乘以一
because we are just multiplying these with ones
非常好的練習，尤其是
very great exercise especially
如果您對這個神經網絡主題不熟悉，這些小細節將
if you are new to this neural network topic these little things will
當您執行內核初始化程序時，這些小細節將真正提供有關發生什麼事的深入了解
will really provide a lot of insight into exactly what's going on when you do kernel initializer
等於正常，例如
equal to he normal for example
我覺得或嘿，正常
i think or hey normal
如果你是那個 hg
if you is that hg
嘿，正常，我覺得那就是你拼寫的方式，是的
hey normal i think that's how you spell it yeah
然後當你
and then when you
然後你可以看到那裡的權重
and then you see the weights right there
是的，你可以將原始輸入定義為全為一，以觀察權重的分佈情況
yeah you can define your original input as all ones to see how the distribution of weights happens
然後你可以，那是一個，那是一個
and then you can that's a that's
那只是一個獨立的講座，所以現在你會知道
that's just separate lecture by itself right so now you'll know
這些分佈的重點，你知道的就在那裡
the importance of you know these distributions right there
好的
okay
所以我
so i
至少希望你知道在這種情況下內核初始化器在做什麼，但更重要的是
at least hope you know what kernel initializer is doing in this case but more importantly
什麼是上採樣
what up sampling means
和
and
對不起，讓我們執行這個，這樣我們可以查看這裡的相同內容
what sorry let's run this so we can look at the same thing here
好的
okay
至少現在你知道升頻的區別了
so at least now you know the difference between up sampling
和可轉置地正常處理
and convertibly transposed normally
我 我
i i
我差點說我會用完樣本
i almost said i would use up sample
但最近我一直在使用 con 2d 轉置
but lately i've been using con 2d transpose
而且我沒有看到結果上有任何明顯的差異
and i haven't seen any visible difference in the results
開啟 開啟
on on
我所處理的一小部分數據集上，但至少這是重要的
on a handful of data sets that i worked with but at least it's important
讓你知道差異在哪裡，我希望這段視頻能達成這個任務
for you to know what the difference is and i hope this video achieves that task
請繼續訂閱這段視頻
please go ahead and subscribe to this video
在下一個部分讓我們繼續這些討論
and in the next one let's continue these discussions
這樣最終我們積累足夠的知識以進行二元語義分割
so eventually we build up enough knowledge to perform semantic segmentation on binary
和多類別
and multi-class
和 3D 多類別
and 3d multi-class
數據集，謝謝大家
data sets thank you guys